A Guide to the Papers of Claude Moore, 1890-2006
Historical Collections, Claude Moore Health Sciences Library
Historical Collections, Claude Moore Health Sciences Library
The Papers of Claude Moore 1890-2006
Historical Collections, Claude Moore Health Sciences Library, University of Virginia
MS-28
5 boxes, 4 linear feet
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
The collection was purchased September 18, 2006 from Crown Collectibles in Chesterfield, Virginia. Items 03/028 through 03/036 and 02/047.8 were already owned by the library.
Biographical/Historical Information
A native of southwest Virginia, Dr. Claude Donald Moore was born in 1892 and died in 1991. He was a 1916 graduate of the medical school at the University of Virginia. Dr. Moore spent his childhood in Radford, Virginia, later moving to Roanoke where he attended high school. Upon his graduation in 1911, Moore took courses at Roanoke College, then crossed the Blue Ridge to Charlottesville where he enrolled at UVa in 1912. That fall, he joined the football team, against the advice of some of his professors, and successfully balanced academics, athletics, and a Pathology Department assistantship for the next four years. These accomplishments were a source of continuing pride to him, along with the 1915 season victory over Yale.
Moore interned at the Cornell Medical Center. With U.S. involvement in World War One eminent, he enlisted in the medical corps and shipped out in the fall of 1918. For a year after the armistice of November 1918, Moore remained in the medical corps in France, attaining the rank of Captain. He returned to private practice in Roanoke in 1920.
General medicine held Moore's interest for six years, but he began to feel the need for additional training. In 1926, the Mayo Clinic accepted him in its radiology program, and he became a specialist in that service. After the Mayo residency, he took the position of full professor and Radiology department head for the George Washington University Hospital in January 1930. Moore remained in the Washington, D.C. area for the rest of his professional career, eventually turning to private practice exclusively. He retired from medicine in 1956. Moore shrewdly capitalized on the regional post-war development boom, and his investments in real estate west of Washington proved immensely lucrative. His philanthropic interests included a $300,000 gift to the University of Virginia Medical School for the library which bears his name. The Claude Moore Charitable Foundation continues to sponsor many worthy projects and has made a $12.5 million challenge gift to UVa's School of Medicine for a state-of-the-art medical education building. Additional genealogical information is in the Sarah Ellen Peterman Horton section of "The Peterman Family" by Marguerite Tise.
Scope and Content
The Claude Moore papers include letters from Moore to his mother, Mrs. Claude E. Moore, also known as Maggie, various holiday cards to his mother, letters to and from other friends and family members, several checks, and announcements. Also included in the collection are two scrapbooks with numerous pictures of Claude Moore; his orders from World War I; newspaper clippings and brochures; his siblings, parents and grandparents; friends; and trips overseas as well as in the United States. Certificates and diplomas include those from high school, college, and medical school.
Arrangement
Box 1 and Box 2 are arranged chronologically. Box 3 is arranged by the page order in the scrapbook. The certificates and diplomas in Box 3 are arranged chronologically. Boxes 4 and 5 contain a second scrapbook.
Contents List
- Letter from Mary to Claude Moore 1916 December 16, 1 ALS 2pp., 1 envelope. (Box-folder 01-001)
  Mary wishes she could spend Christmas with Moore.
- Letter from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore ca. 1918, 1 ALS 2 pp. (Box-folder 01-002)
  Moore discusses having his first operation: a tonsillectomy at the Mayo Clinic
- Envelope from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore ca. 1918-19, 1 envelope. (Box-folder 01-003)
- Envelope from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore ca. 1918-19, 1 envelope. (Box-folder 01-004)
- Envelope from Claude Moore to Helen Moore ca. 1918-19, 1 envelope. (Box-folder 01-005)
- Envelope from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore ca. 1918-19, 1 envelope. (Box-folder 01-006)
- Envelope from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore ca. 1918-19, 1 envelope. (Box-folder 01-007)
- Letter from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore ca. 1918 March 29, 1 ALS 2 pp., 1 envelope. (Box-folder 01-008)
  Moore says Chicago is not to be compared to New York and doesn't even have a subway.
- Envelope from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1918 April 29, 1 envelope. (Box-folder 01-009)
- Letter from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore and kids 1918 May 31, 1 ALS 4 pp., 1 envelope. (Box-folder 01-010)
  Moore is a ward surgeon and has to take orders from only two other people. His camp, Camp Dodge in Iowa, had sent 15,000 men east in two weeks.
- Envelope from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1918 September 15, 1 envelope. (Box-folder 01-011)
  The envelope is postmarked Brooklyn, N.Y.
- Postcard from Claude Moore to Mr. Claude E. Moore 1918 September-October, 1 postcard with AN. (Box-folder 01-012)
  Postcard states that the ship on which Moore sailed is safely overseas.
- Envelope from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1918 October 4, 1 envelope. (Box-folder 01-013)
- Envelope from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1918 October 11, 1 envelope. (Box-folder 01-014)
- Envelope from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1918 October 14, 1 envelope. (Box-folder 01-015)
- Letter from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1918 October 20, 1 ALS 2 pp., 1 envelope. (Box-folder 01-016)
  Moore is working as hard as he ever has since being in the army. He is a ward surgeon with many patients but no nurses. He cannot disclose his location.
- Envelope from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1918 October 25, 1 envelope. (Box-folder 01-017)
- Envelope from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1918 November, 1 envelope. (Box-folder 01-018)
- Envelope from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1918 November 4, 1 envelope. (Box-folder 01-019)
- Envelope from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1918 November 7, 1 envelope. (Box-folder 01-020)
- Letter from Claude Moore to Katherine Moore 1918 November 11, 1 ALS 2pp., 1 envelope. (Box-folder 01-021)
  Moore compliments his youngest sister on her writing ability. He says the war will be over soon, but it will be the following summer before he will be home as the patients will continue to need care.
- Letter from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1918 November 16, 1 TL 1p., 1 envelope. (Box-folder 01-022)
  Moore visited a tank school and saw 200 camouflaged tanks. He says that everyone is collecting souvenirs. His duty is to "amuse" the center so he showing pictures and going to dances.
- Letter from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1918 November 17, 1 TLS 1 p., 1 envelope. (Box-folder 01-023)
  Moore complains about his mother not writing enough and threatens to "marry me a French girl and make me a home over here." He hopes to go forward into the Zone of Advance rather than return to the States. He wants Kodak film which could not be found in Paris.
- Letter from Claude Moore to Helen 1918 November 21, 1 TLS 2pp. (Box-folder 01-024)
  Moore scolds his sister for not writing. He says his hospital is entirely empty. He is anxious to see the old front and does not want the war debt that France owes the U.S. to be cancelled.
- Letter from Claude Moore to Mr. Claude E. Moore 1918 November 25, 1 envelope. (Box-folder 01-025)
- Envelope from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1918 November 29, 1 envelope. (Box-folder 01-026)
- Letter from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1918 December 9, 1 TLS 1p., 1 envelope. (Box-folder 01-027)
  Moore has been appointed Amusement and Athletic Director of the new Red Cross building. He has heard that the flu is about over in the U.S. and that twice as many people died in the states from the flu as American soldiers died in WWI.
- Letter from Claude Moore to Helen Moore 1918 December 19, 1 ALS 2pp., 1 envelope, 1 menu card. (Box-folder 01-028)
  Moore wears his hip boots so doesn't mind the mud so much though would like to be someplace sunnier. He mentions various dances, states he was "kind of master of ceremonies," and obtained Christmas trees for each ward.
- Letter from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1918 December 26, 1 TLS 1p., 1 envelope. (Box-folder 01-029)
  Moore is working 14 hours days. He writes, "Christmas for me was as it should be doing some thing for the other fellow and to make him happy." He describes the Christmas packages the patients received and has seen [President] Wilson.
- Letter from John S. Arnold to Edith F. Moore 1919, 1 TD 2pp., 1 TL 1p., 1 envelope. (Box-folder 01-030)
  Arnold from the Central Teachers' Agency is offering to help place teachers.
- Envelope from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1919, 1 envelope. (Box-folder 01-031)
- Envelope from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1919, 1 envelope. (Box-folder 01-032)
- Envelope from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1919, 1 envelope. (Box-folder 01-033)
- Envelope to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1919, 1 envelope. (Box-folder 01-034)
- Letter from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1919 January 3, 1 TLS 2pp., 1 envelope. (Box-folder 01-035)
  Moore writes that Base Hospital 88 is moving to Savenay. He has been asked to stay where he is to run the amusements and athletics program, but want to move and see as much as he can. He describes the amusements, wants Kodak film, and sees that flu is breaking out again.
- Letter from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1919 January 14, 1 ALS 1p., 1 envelope. (Box-folder 01-036)
  Moore is disappointed in Paris compared to N.Y. and encourages his mother to avoid the flu.
- Letter from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore [1919] 1918 January 19, 1 ALS 4pp. (Box-folder 01-037)
  Moore has arrived at Savenay, west of Nantes and describes his exploration of Paris. He has visited the UVA Hospital (Base Hospital 41).
- Letter from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1919 February 4, 1 ALS 2pp., 1 envelope. (Box-folder 01-038)
  Moore is the most contented of any in B. H. # 88. He would like to be home for a few days and then go back to France. He has seen more of the world in six months than ever before.
- Letter from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore and folks 1919 February 9, 1 TLS 1p., 1 envelope. (Box-folder 01-039)
  Moore writes that no combatant troops would leave France until "this Russian situation had been settled." The Hospital has 2000 patients. He wants more film, has saved $1000, seen most of France, and is ready to start on the other countries.
- Letter from Lewis Crenshaw to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1919 February 16, 1 TLS 1p., 1 envelope. (Box-folder 01-040)
  Crenshaw represents the University of Virginia European Bureau and is enclosing a photo of Moore.
- Letter from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1919 February 16, 1 TLS 1p., 1 envelope. (Box-folder 01-041)
  Moore says no way to tell when everyone will get home.
- Envelope from Claude Moore to Katherine Moore 1919 February 18, 1 envelope. (Box-folder 01-042)
- Letter from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1919 March 3, 1 ALS 2pp., 1 envelope. (Box-folder 01-043)
  Moore is concerned about what he will do upon his return to the U.S. He asks his mother to ask his father if he will give him work and how much he will pay. His last was "1.75," and he wants more than that and less to do.
- Letter from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1919 March 10, 1 ALS 3pp., 1 envelope. (Box-folder 01-044)
  Moore is in charge of two wards and has been recommended for a promotion from lieutenant to captain, but doesn't think he'll get it as he is the second youngest doctor in B. H. 88.
- Letter from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1919 March 15, 1 ALS 2pp., 1 envelope. (Box-folder 01-045)
  Moore is getting anxious to see home, but would like the most to visit home and then return to Europe for six months.
- Letter from Claude Moore to Helen Moore 1919 March 26, 1 ALS 2pp., 1 envelope. (Box-folder 01-046)
  Moore mentions the many places he has seen on his travels through Europe.
- Envelope from Claude Moore to Miss C. E. Moore 1919 April 1, 1 envelope. (Box-folder 01-047)
- "Virginia University Men to Gather in Paris To-Day" 1919 April 12, 1 newspaper clipping 1 p. (Box-folder 01-048)
  Jefferson Day ceremonies
- The New York Herald. Paris. "University of Virginia Alumni in Paris Honor Thomas Jefferson" 1919 April 13, 1 newspaper clipping 1 p. (Box-folder 01-049)
- Letter from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1919 April 25, 1 ALS 3pp., 1 envelope. (Box-folder 01-050)
  Moore is concerned about what he will do when he returns home.
- Letter from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1919 May 11, 1 ALS 2pp., 1 envelope. (Box-folder 01-051)
  Moore reflects on he past year. One year earlier he left Rochester, MN for Iowa and army life. Now he is a captain.
- Letter from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1919 May 18, 1 ALS 2pp., 1 envelope. (Box-folder 01-052)
  Moore writes that his correspondence is regular only with his mother. He has thought about signing up with the Red Cross and going to Poland or Armenia.
- Letter from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1919 May 26, 1 ALS 2pp. (Box-folder 01-053)
  Moore says that all the sick and injured men in France come to the port he is at on the way home so he is very busy. He is thinking about staying in the service when he returns to the U.S. and can make $2000 a year.
- Letter from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore, Sisters, and Mr. Claude e. Moore 1919 May 31, 1 ALS 2pp., 1 envelope. (Box-folder 01-054)
  Moore is working harder than anytime since joining the army as the hospitals toward the front are closing and sending their patients to his hospital. He says he owes all that he is to his mother more than anyone else and also that he owes a lot to his dad and others.
- Envelope from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1919 June 17, 1 envelope. (Box-folder 01-055)
- Letter from Claude Moore to Katherine Moore, sisters and folks 1919 June 23, 1 ALS 2pp., 1 envelope. (Box-folder 01-056)
  Moore says his hospital is one of two still treating patients. There are 2000 officers at the ports awaiting passage home.
- Letter from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1919 July 8, 1 ALS 1p., 1 envelope. (Box-folder 01-057)
  Moore says in another couple weeks there will be no patients.
- Letter from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1919 July 25, 1 ALS 3pp., 1 envelope. (Box-folder 01-058)
  Moore is back in the U.S. at Camp Merritt, N.J. He is accompanying troops to home camps with returns to Camp Merritt for more.
- Letter from Mrs. P. K. Sherfy to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1938 November 30, 1 ALS 2pp., 1 envelope, 1 envelope fragment. (Box-folder 01-059)
  Sherfy has finished Mrs. Moore's quilt for $4.00.
- Christmas card from Betty Alice Boyes ca. 1940s, 1 card. (Box-folder 01-060)
- Christmas card from Jake and Mabel ca. 1940s, 1 card. (Box-folder 01-061)
- Birthday card from David Boyes to Mrs. Claude E. Moore ca. 1940s, 1 card, 1 envelope. (Box-folder 01-062)
- Valentine from Shirley Smiley to Mrs. Claude E. Moore ca. 1940s, 1 card. (Box-folder 01-063)
- Valentine to Mrs. Claude E. Moore ca. 1940s, 1 card. (Box-folder 01-064)
- Thank you card from Billy Dulaney ca. 1940s, 1 card. (Box-folder 01-065)
- Birthday card from Helen and Randolph to Mrs. Claude E. Moore ca. 1940s, 1 card. (Box-folder 01-066)
- Christmas card from the Heasons ca. 1940s, 1 card. (Box-folder 01-067)
- Checking account brochures post 1943 July 1, 2 brochures, 1 envelope. (Box-folder 01-068)
  Envelope addressed to Mrs. Maggie M. Moore or Mary Katherine
- Letter from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1944 October 21, 1 ALS 2pp., 1 envelope. (Box-folder 01-069)
  Moore mentions the crops and working hard in his office.
- Christmas card from Laura B. Taylor to Mrs. Claude E. Moore and folks 1944 December 23, 1 card with AN, 1 envelope. (Box-folder 01-070)
  Taylor is a cousin.
- Birthday card from Martha Boyes to Mrs. Claude E. Moore ca. 1945, 1 card, 1 envelope. (Box-folder 01-071)
- Letter from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1945 January 5, 1 TLS with AN 1p., 1 envelope. (Box-folder 01-072)
  Moore discusses Christmas travel difficulties, the farm, need for exercise,and the bad war news.
- Letter from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1945 February 10, 1 TLS with AN 1p., 1 envelope. (Box-folder 01-073)
  Moore says there is little or no prospect of additional help at the farm until the war ends.
- Letter from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1945 May 4, 1 TLS with AN 1p., 1 postcard, 1 envelope. (Box-folder 01-074)
  Moore says the war is in the exciting stage with the future, both immediate and distant, uncertain.
- Letter from Margaret [A. Bauer] to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1945 May 15, 1 ALS 2pp. (Box-folder 01-075)
  Margaret and Claude Moore return from Roanoke in time to help deliver Gertrude's 10th baby.
- Birthday card from Shirley Smiley to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1945 May 17, 1 card, 1 envelope. (Box-folder 01-076)
- Letter from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1945 June 5, 1 TLS with AN 1p., 1 envelope. (Box-folder 01-077)
  Moore asks his mother to save and send him any spare blue points, used to acquire rationed processed goods.
- Letter from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1945 June 29, 1 TLS with AN 1p., 1 envelope. (Box-folder 01-078)
  Moore has learned that very few medical personnel will be let out of the army before the first of the year so will work on.
- Letter from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1945 July 30, 1 TLS with AN 1p., 1 map, 1 TD. (Box-folder 01-079)
  Moore announces he has purchased a "real" farm. According to two enclosures it is the Dekay Farm of 605 acres near Washington D.C. and was for sale for $30,000. Moore says it can be developed into one of the show places of Loudoun County.
- Letter from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1945 August 29, 1 TLS with AN 1p., 1 envelope. (Box-folder 01-080)
  Moore is planning a trip to Maine and says he may have to hitch-hike part of the way.
- Letter from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1945 September 20, 1 TLS with AN 1p., 1 envelope. (Box-folder 01-081)
  Moore writes that few doctors are getting out of the army so he sees no immediate help or relief. He sends a check to be cashed only if part of it is used for transportation to visit him.
- Letter from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1945 December 17, 1 TLS with AN 1p., 1 envelope. (Box-folder 01-082)
  Moore is planning to drive to Roanoke with his father and is expecting someone, particularly his mother, to drive back with him. He still has no help and is tired.
- Letter from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1945 December 27, 1 TLS with AN 1p., 1 envelope. (Box-folder 01-083)
  Moore returned home and is back at work.
- Letter from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1946 January 10, 1 TLS with AN 1p., 1 envelope. (Box-folder 02-001)
  Moore has been sick, but still working. He says winter ties him and his mother in too closely. There are only dial phones in Washington.
- Letter from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1946 January 1 [], 1 ALS 1p., 1 envelope. (Box-folder 02-002)
  Moore is not sleeping well and encourages his mother to visit.
- Train ticket from Roanoke to Washington D.C. 1946 January 22, 1 train ticket. (Box-folder 02-003)
- Letter from Claude Moore to Mr. Claude E. Moore 1946 February 14, 1 TLS with AN 1p. (Box-folder 02-004)
  Moore is planning a trip home, will return probably with his mother, and invites his father to come back with him.
- Letter from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1946 February 26, 1 postcard. (Box-folder 02-005)
  Moore returned safely to Lanesmore and planted al the shrubs and trees.
- Letter from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1946 March 19, 1 TLS with AN 1p., 1 envelope. (Box-folder 02-006)
  Moore is hiring someone to help him with repairs.
- Letter from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1946 April 25, 1 ALS 2pp., 1 envelope. (Box-folder 02-007)
  Moore's work is becoming more and more monotonous. There is electricity to the barnyard, but not the house.
- Envelope addressed to Claude Moore 1946 April 29, 1 envelope fragment. (Box-folder 02-008)
  The envelope has been refolded, re-stamped, and sent to Mrs. Claude E. Moore.
- Mother's Day card to Grandmother from Shirley [Smiley] ca. 1946 May, 1 card. (Box-folder 02-009)
- Birthday card from Helen to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1946 May 10, 1 card with ANS, 1 envelope. (Box-folder 02-010)
- Letter from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1946 May 10, 1 ALS 1p., 1 envelope. (Box-folder 02-011)
- Commencement invitation and program for the Woman's College of UNC 1946 May 14, 1 card, 1 invitation, 1 program, 1 envelope. (Box-folder 02-012)
  The graduate is Shirley Virginia Smiley.
- Birthday card from Ruth G. Shannon to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1946 May 14, 1 card, 1 envelope. (Box-folder 02-013)
- Birthday card from Mrs. Carroll and Martha to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1946 May 17, 1 card, 1 envelope. (Box-folder 02-014)
- Letter from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1946 June 28, 1 TLS with AN 1p., 1 envelope. (Box-folder 02-015)
  Moore says the house finally has electricity, but states that butter, lard, etc. are not available. Send a check.
- Postcard from Shirley [Smiley] to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1946 June 29, 1 postcard with AN. (Box-folder 02-016)
- Letter from Katherine to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1946 July 2, 1 ALS 2pp., 1 envelope. (Box-folder 02-017)
  Katherine describes to her mother her time visiting Moore.
- Letter from Katherine to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1946 July 8, 1 ALS 1p., 1 envelope. (Box-folder 02-018)
  Katherine thanks her mother for sending butter and plans to be home by the middle of the month.
- Letter from F. G. Horton to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1946 august 18, 1 ALS 2pp., 6 postcards, 1 envelope. (Box-folder 02-019)
  Horton wants to hear from Maggie [Mrs. Moore] in regard to her interest in the home place.
- Letter from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1946 August 20, 1 TLS with AN 1p., 1 envelope. (Box-folder 02-020)
  Several women from the farm were arrested for stealing, including Gertrude. he sends a check.
- Letter from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1946 September 27, 1 TLS with AN 1p., 1 envelope. (Box-folder 02-021)
  Moore has a new technician and misses the national x-ray meeting for the first time in 16 years. Gertrude was convicted of larceny and jailed.
- Letter from Margaret A. Bauer to Mrs. Claude E. Moore, Letter from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore, and Letter from Katherine to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1947 January 1, 3 ALS 4pp., 1 envelope. (Box-folder 02-022)
  Margaret thanks Mrs. Moore for her hospitality over Christmas. Moore wishes he had Christmas to look forward to without waiting a whole year. Katherine describes their new year celebration.
- Beckley Post-Herald "Miss Shirley Smiley Returns to Norfolk, Va." 1947 January 3, 1 newspaper clipping 1p. (Box-folder 02-023)
- Commencement invitation from Auburn High School in Riner, Virginia for Mrs. Claude E. Moore and family 1947 May 23, 1 invitation, 1 card, 1 envelope. (Box-folder 02-024)
  The graduate is Frances Dulaney
- Announcement of commencement for Woodrow Wilson High School in Beckley, WV 1947 May 28, 1 announcement. (Box-folder 02-025)
- Letter from Claude Moore to Mrs. Claude E. Moore 1947 August 8, 1 TLS with AN 1p., 1 envelope. (Box-folder 02-026)
  The farm production has been exceptionally good. Moore sends a check for $100 and will send more if he is told how the $100 is used.